Gansheng Tan, Ph.D. Student

Washington University School of Medicine, 520 S Euclid Ave, St. Louis, MO, 63110 Phone: +1 (314) 745-9303, Email: gan.t@wustl.edu

Research Interest

I am a **self-motivated** and **team-minded Ph.D.** student with **5 years** of experience in **neuromodulation** research and bioelectrical signal processing. I seek to understand neural plasticity through electrophysiology, interact with these signals using an interdisciplinary approach, and thereby develop new effective treatments for nervous system-related diseases.

Education

09/2019 – present
 MO, USA.
 Ph.D. Biomedical Engineering
 Washington University in St. Louis
 09/2019 – 03/2022
 M.Eng. Mechanical Engineering

Shanghai, China Shanghai Jiao Tong University

06/2017 – 09/2019 Diplôme d'ingénieur (postgraduate degree in engineering)

Île-de-France, CentraleSupélec

France Topics: Advanced Statistics, Machine Learning, Signal Processing

09/2015 - 06/2019 **B.Eng**.

Shanghai, China Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Research and Professional Appointments

09/2021 - present **Research Scholar**

St. Louis, MO, USA Department of Neurosurgery, Washington University School of Medicine

Studying the neurophysiological effects of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation; investigating the interaction between cortical oscillation and muscle

synergies

11/2019 – 03/2022 Graduate Research Assistant

Shanghai, China Department of Rehabilitation Medicine (Ruijin Hospital) - State Key Laboratory of

Mechanical Systems and Vibration, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Developed a framework based on Electroencephalography and Electromyography for individualizing Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation to promote recovery from

stroke

05/2019 - 09/2019 **Research Fellow**

Bron, France Lyon Neuroscience Research Center, French National Institute of Health and

Medical Research

Analyzed the cerebral oscillations underlying the meditative practices; developed

semi-automatic EEG signal preprocessing pipeline for meditation research

01/2018 – 03/2021 Graduate Research Assistant

Île-de-France, Signals and Systems Laboratory, French National Centre for Scientific Research

France Identified neural correlates of Focused Attention meditation and problem-solving

Identified neural correlates of Focused Attention meditation and problem-solving state; developed a platform guiding meditators based on mental state classification

10/2015 – 05/2017 Undergraduate Research Assistant

Shanghai, China State Key Laboratory of Mechanical Systems, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Skills

Software Engineering (Python, R, MATLAB, Github, Java, C/C++, HTML, CSS, 8 years)

Statistical Learning and Biomedical Data Analysis (5 years)

Clinical and Translational Research (3 years)

Scientific Writing and Illustration (Adobe Illustrator, MS Office, Latex, 5 years)

Awards

2021	2021 China National Scholarship (top 0.5%)
2020	Changjiang Siyuan Scholarship, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China
2018	Top 10 in Huawei Big Data Challenge in France
2018	Innovative Project Award, CS ² Congrès Scientifique du Campus de Saclay, France
2017	Écoles Centrales Group – Chinese Universities Double Degree Scholarship, China
2016	Honor Student, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China
2015	Excellent Design, Engineering Design Showcase, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China

Experience

10/2018 - 05/2019	Teaching Fellow
-------------------	------------------------

Île-de-France, Laboratory in Mathematics and Computer Science (MICS), CentraleSupélec

France Instructor for Convergence, Integration, Probability and Partial Differential Equation

08/2018 – 05/2019 Vice President of International Student Union

Île-de-France, CentraleSupélec

France

04/2018 - 05/2018 **Exchange Student**

Cambridge, U.K. Department of Engineering, University of Cambridge

10/2017 – 06/2018 **Project Manager**

Paris, France Tech for Good Explorer & La Condamine

Professional societies

Graduate Student Member of IEEE

Graduate Student Member of American Society of Neurorehabilitation

Publications

Tan, G. et al. A framework for quantifying the effects of transcranial magnetic stimulation on motor recovery from hemiparesis: Corticomuscular Network. Journal of Neural Engineering (2022).

Tan, G., Wang, J., Liu, J., Sheng, Y., Xie, Q., Brunner, P., Liu, H. Towards the Optimization of Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation for Motor Recovery from Hemiparesis: Study of Corticomuscular Network. 2022 American Society of Neurorehabilitation Annual Meeting.

Tan, G., Xu, K., Liu, J. & Liu, H. A Trend on Autism Spectrum Disorder Research: Eye Tracking-EEG Correlative Analytics. IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems 1–1 (2021).

Liu, J., Tan, G., Wang, J., Wei, Y., Sheng, Y., Chang, H., Xie, Q., & Liu, H. Closed-loop construction and analysis of cortico-muscular-cortical functional network after stroke. **IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging** 1–1 (2022).

Liu, J., Tan, G., Sheng, Y., Wei, Y. & Liu, H. A Novel Delay Estimation Method for Improving Corticomuscular Coherence in Continuous Synchronization Events. **IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering** vol. 69 1328–1339 (2022).

Liu, J., **Tan, G.**, Sheng, Y. & Liu, H. Multiscale Transfer Spectral Entropy for Quantifying Corticomuscular Interaction. **IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics** vol. 25 2281–2292 (2021).

- Liu, J., Wang, J., **Tan, G.**, Sheng, Y., Chang, H., Xie, Q., & Liu, H. (2021). Correlation Evaluation of Functional Corticomuscular Coupling With Abnormal Muscle Synergy After Stroke. **IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering** vol. 68 3261–3272 (2021).
- Liu, J., **Tan, G.**, Sheng, Y., Wang, J., Lu, W., & Liu, H. Delay estimation for cortical-muscular interaction via the rate of voxels change. 2020 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC) (2020)
- **Tan G.**, Wang S., Vierge V., Mu W., Wang M., Greco L., Mounier H., Chaillet A. An EEG classifier to discriminate between focused attention meditation and problem-solving task (**Submitted**).